# Changho Shin

cshin23@wisc.edu https://ch-shin.github.io 1210 W Dayton St, Madison, WI 53706

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research is focused on **foundation models**, including **large language models** and **multimodal foundation models**. Some of my work aims to efficiently help these models adopt new skills. This involves two prongs: (1) approaches for obtaining and selecting fine-tuning data, often by using a strategy called **weak supervision** and (2) efficient adaptation, including training-free approaches like **representation** editing.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of Wisconsin-Madison

Sep. 2020 -

- Ph.D. Computer Science, M.S. Mathematics
- Advisor: Professor Frederic Sala

#### Seoul National University

Mar. 2015 – Feb. 2017

- M.S. Machine Learning
- Advisor: Professor Wonjong Rhee

#### Seoul National University

Mar. 2011 - Feb. 2015

- B.A. in Psychology, B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering
- Graduated with honors (Cum Laude)

# HONORS & AWARDS

Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Finalist	2024
Best Paper Award Honorable Mention (NeurIPS R0-FoMo Workshop)	2023
NeurIPS 2023 Scholar Award	2023
Winner in DataComp competition (Filtering Track, Small)	2023
CS Departmental Scholarship (University of Wisconsin-Madison)	2020

### CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

- [C5] Changho Shin, Jitian Zhao, Sonia Cromp, Harit Vishwakarma, Frederic Sala, "OTTER: Improving Zero-Shot Classification via Optimal Transport", Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2024.
- [C4] Dyah Adila\*, Changho Shin\*, Linrong Cai, Frederic Sala, "Zero-Shot Robustification of Zero-Shot Models With Auxiliary Foundation Models", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2024.
  Workshop version [W1]: Best Paper Award Honorable Mention, Oral Presentation at NeurIPS 2023 R0-FoMo Workshop.
- [C3] Changho Shin, Sonia Cromp, Dyah Adila, Frederic Sala, "Mitigating Source Bias for Fairer Weak Supervision", Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023.
- [C2] Changho Shin, Winfred Li, Harit Vishwakarma, Nicholas Roberts, Frederic Sala, "Universalizing Weak Supervision", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022.
- [C1] Changho Shin, Sunghwan Joo, Jaeryun Yim, Hyoseop Lee, Taesup Moon, Wonjong Rhee, "Subtask Gated Networks for Non-Intrusive Load Monitoring", AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2019.

# JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- [J2] Changho Shin, Eunjung Lee, Jeongyun Han, Jaeryun Yim, Hyoseop Lee, Wonjong Rhee, "The ENERTALK Dataset, 15 Hz Electricity Consumption Data from 22 Houses in Korea", *Nature Scientific Data*, 2019 (Impact Factor = 5.929).
- [J1] **Changho Shin**, Seungeun Rho, Hyoseop Lee, Wonjong Rhee, "Data Requirements for Applying Machine Learning to Energy Disaggregation", *Energies*, May 2019 (Impact Factor = 2.707).

#### WORKSHOP **PUBLICATIONS**

- [W4] Dyah Adila\*, Changho Shin\*, Linrong Cai, Frederic Sala, "Foundation Models Can Robustify Themselves, For Free", NeurIPS 2023 R0-FoMo Workshop. Best Paper Award Honorable Mention, Oral Presentation.
- [W3] Changho Shin\*, Joon Suk Huh\*, Elina Choi, "Pool-Search-Demonstrate: Improving Data-wrangling LLMs via better in-context examples", NeurIPS 2023 Table Representation Learning (TRL) Workshop. Oral Presentation.
- [W2] Changho Shin\*, Tzu-heng Huang\*, Sui Jiet Tay, Dyah Adila, Frederic Sala, "Multimodal Data Curation via Object Detection and Filter Ensembles", ICCV 2023 Datacomp Workshop (Rank #1 in DataComp competition filtering track (small)).
- [W1] Changho Shin, Alice Schoenauer-Sebag, "Can we get smarter than majority vote? Efficient use of individual rater's labels for content moderation", NeurIPS Efficient Natural Language and Speech Processing (ENLSP) Workshop, 2022.

#### **PREPRENTS**

- [P3] Changho Shin, John Cooper, Dyah Adila, Frederic Sala, "Weak-to-Strong Generalization Through the Data-Centric Lens", Under Review, 2024.
- [P2] Dyah Adila, Changho Shin, Yijing Zhang, Frederic Sala, "Is Free Self-alignment Possible?", Under Review, 2024.
- [P1] Yijing Zhang, Dyah Adila, Changho Shin, Frederic Sala, "Personalize Your LLM: Fake it then Align it", Under Review, 2024.

### JOB **EXPERIENCE**

### Snorkel AI, California, USA

Jun. 2024 -

Research Intern

• Mentor: Christopher Glaze, Paroma Varma

#### Twitter, San Francisco, USA

Jun. 2022 - Aug. 2022

ML Engineer Intern

- Mentor: Alice Schoenauer Sebag Manager: Milind Ganjoo
- Improving toxicity classification via weak supervision [W4]

# Encored Technologies, Seoul, Korea

Jan. 2018 - Jul. 2020

Data Scientist

- Advisor: Dr. Hyoseop Lee
- Non-intrusive load monitoring [C4, J1, J2], Energy forecasting

Korea Institute for Defense Analyses, Seoul, Korea Researcher

Jan. 2017 – Dec. 2017

## **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

#### University of Wisconsin-Madison

• Teaching assistant for CS 839 (Foundation Models)

Fall 2023

• Teaching assistant for CS 300 (Programming II) • Teaching assistant for CS 760 (Machine Learning) Fall 2022, Spring 2023 Fall 2021, Spring 2022

• Teaching assistant for CS 320 (Data Programming II)

Spring 2021

• Teaching assistant for CS 220 (Data Programming I)

Fall 2020

### GRADUATE COURSEWORK

- M2680.001300 Machine Learning for Information Studies @ SNU
- M2680.001400 Social Computing @ SNU
- 493.613 Mathematics for Intelligent Systems (Numerical Linear Algebra) @ SNU
- 493.701 Learning and Applications of Deep Neural Networks @ SNU
- M0000.005400 Convex Optimization @ SNU
- M0000.005400 Neural Networks @ SNU
- CS537 Introduction to Operating Systems @ UW
- CS639.004 Introduction to Computational Learning Theory @ UW
- CS726 Nonlinear Optimization 1
- CS744 Big Data Systems @ UW

- CS761 Mathematical Foundations of Machine Learning @ UW
- CS784 Foundations of Data Management @ UW
- CS787 Advanced Algorithms @ UW
- CS839 Probability and Learning in High Dimension @ UW
- CS880 Advanced Topics in Learning Theory @ UW
- Math521 Analysis I @ UW
- Math522 Analysis II @ UW
- Math551 Elementary Topology @ UW
- Math629 Introduction to Measure and Integration @ UW
- Math621 Analysis III (Analysis on Manifolds) @ UW
- Math721 A First Course in Real Analysis @ UW
- Math733 Theory of Probability I @ UW
- Math734 Theory of Probability II @ UW Math761 Differentiable Manifolds @ UW
- Math833 Modern Discrete Probability @ UW
- Math<br/>888 Randomized Linear Algebra @ UW
- Stat992 Optimal Transport and Applications to Machine Learning @ UW

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

# Machine Learning / Deep Learning / Data Science

PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, scikit-learn, NumPy, Pandas, SciPy

#### **DBMS**

MySQL, MongoDB, PySpark

#### Research & Development Tools

Visual Studio Code, Jupyter, PyCharm, Docker, GitHub, CircleCI, Shell, AWS

#### **Programming Languages**

Python, R, MATLAB, Java, Go, C, LATEX